

CONTACT INFO

- Bangalore, India
- arun.srinivasan@outlook.in
- +91 81237 61771
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/c4arun/
- https://srinivasan-arun.github.io/cv/

SKILLS SUMMARY

Engineering Management

Software Development

Process Improvement

Resource Planning

Tech Design

Microservices

Event-Driven Architecture

Cloud

- AWS
- GCP

DevOps

- Jenkins
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- ELK
- App Monitoring ToolsGrafana, Prometheus

Full Stack Web Development

- Angular
- ReactJS (Micro Front-Ends)
- Java/JEE
- Spring Boot
- Vert.X
- PWA
- NodeJS
- Elastic Search
- MySQL, MongoDB
- Apache Kafka
- Redis

Tools

- JIRA
- Git
- Confluence
- Bitbucket

ARUN SRINIVASAN

ENGINEERING MANAGER

SUMMARY

Engineering Manager having 9+ years of experience in IT industry. I act as an intermediary between the business and technical teams to understand business requirements, define the technical architecture required and support development & engineering teams with implementation and drive engineering excellence by improving processes around DevOps, Agile. Committed to efficiently completing projects by leveraging available engineering talent.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Engineering Manager

BetterPlace | Apr 2019 - present

- Bootstrapped the next-gen Platform 2.0 approach for all products with the aim to move towards a SaaS-based business model.
- Handled migration of a complex monolith application to highly scalable event-driven micro-services based product model.
- Conduct day-to-day project coordination, planning, and implementation across multiple teams.
- Translated requirements into polished, high-level designs
- Implemented and improved processes around DevOps, Agile and ensured high-quality product delivery within the given timeline.
- Recruit, Coach, Mentor, Motivate and Lead a team of Engineers.
- Be a champion of engineering excellence establish team metrics for measurement of engineering and operational excellence. Implement a consistent, regular process for assessment and improvement

Application Team Lead

Unisys India | Jul 2012 - Mar 2019

- Worked on many complex web projects from the scratch majorly in Public-Sector and Transportation Domain.
- Hands-on experience in implementing IoT-based solution.
- Hands-on experience on complex Java/JEE, NodeJS based web development

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Coimbatore Institute of Technology, Anna University

B.E in Computer Science | Jun 2008 - Apr 2012

• CGPA 8.56

S.K.V Higher Secondary School, TamilNadu

Higher Secondary Education | Jun 2006 - Apr 2008

• Percentage - 95%